momspective.com 2013-11-03

# Privacy Policy | Momspective

Momspective-  Web Site Privacy Statement

Last Updated: January 9, 2013

SCOPE OF POLICY

At Momspective, we respect your privacy rights and are committed to protecting the information we collect from you online. To further this commitment, we have developed the following Website Privacy Policy which explains how we collect, use, disclose, and protect information you provide to us on any of the websites covered by this agreement. This Privacy Policy applies only to information submitted and collected online through a Website we operate or authorize. It does not apply to information we collect offline unless, with your permission, that information is combined with information collected or submitted online. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected on websites operated by our parent, subsidiaries or other third parties.

UPDATES TO POLICY

Occasionally, we will revise and update this Privacy Policy. Please check back from time to time to ensure that you are aware of any changes to our privacy practices. If we revise this Privacy Policy, the last updated date above will be changed. If we make a major change to this Privacy Policy, we will post a notice of the change on all of the Websites.

INFORMATION COLLECTED ABOUT YOU

In order to give you the best experience on our Websites, we may collect personal and non-personal information about you. Non-personal information includes anonymous information such as demographic data. Under all circumstances, we will only collect the information deemed reasonably necessary to fulfill your online requests and our legitimate business objectives. Please read below for a description of each type of information collected.

# Personal Information is information that can be used to identify you such as your name, address, telephone number, or email address. We do not collect any Personal Information about you unless you choose to provide it to us. If you choose not to provide Personal Information, you may be unable to use certain features on our Websites.

# Demographic information is anonymous information such as your age, date of birth, gender, hobbies, interests, zip/postal code or country. If demographic information is collected for an activity that also requires Personal Information, we may combine the demographic information with your Personal Information. Combining data allows us to customize the notices we send you and the content we provide you according to your interests and preferences. Demographic information is not considered Personal Information unless it is linked to Personal Information about a specific user. If you choose not to provide certain demographic information, you may not be able to use certain features on our Websites.

# Aggregate information is anonymous data about individuals that is grouped together to study a group or category of services or users. Aggregate information is not considered Personal Information unless it is linked to Personal Information about a specific user.

COLLECTION AND USE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We may request Personal and demographic information to respond to your requests and provide services to you such as: registering for and participating in Giveaways and contests ; sending email newsletters; participating in online contests and sweepstakes; and sending email correspondence. Each category below describes how we handle the requested information.

Online Contests and Sweepstakes

To enter our online contests and sweepstakes, you may be required to provide us with certain Personal and/or demographic information about yourself. To learn more about the information collected and used for a specific contest or sweepstakes, please see the official contest or sweepstakes rules.

Email Correspondence and Other Communication

We may respond to your email correspondence and communications if such correspondence includes a return email address. Because an email address is Personal Information, we protect the privacy of the sender by limiting access to these email messages. Only administrators with a legitimate business need to access the emails are allowed to do so. For quality control purposes, email messages may be kept for a period of time. There may, however, be certain cases where hard copies may be kept on file, such as emails concerning forum questions or complaints. Information from email messages will not be used for marketing purposes and will be maintained in a secure location.

Online Interaction

Some of our Websites may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or newsgroups (â€Public Forumsâ€) available to users. Please remember that any information disclosed in Public Forums becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding whether to disclose your Personal Information in these Public Forums. We do not individuals under the age of 18 to participate in Public Forums.

DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We do not sell or rent Personal Information to third parties. We may share Personal Information with vendors who help us perform various internal functions necessary to operate our business. We may disclose Personal Information (a) in the good faith belief that we are required to do so by law; (b) if doing so is reasonably necessary to comply with legal process; (c) to respond to any claims; (d) to enforce the terms and conditions of our Websites; or (e) to protect the rights, property, or personal safety of Momspective, our readers, or the public. We also may disclose your email address to our partners solely to send you email messages you have requested, or to ensure that you do not receive such messages if you have opted out of receiving them. Any vendors or partners with whom we may share Personal Information are permitted to obtain only the Personal Information they need to deliver the services requested. They are required to maintain the confidentiality of the information and are prohibited from using it for any other purpose.

In addition, information about our customers, including Personal Information, may be disclosed as part of any merger, sale, transfer of company assets, or acquisition, if permitted by and done in accordance with applicable laws.

DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use cookies on some of our Websites. Cookies are small text files that a website places on your hard drive whenever you visit the Website. These files identify your computer and record your preferences and other data about your visit so that when you return to the Website, it knows who you are and can personalize your visit. Cookies may be linked to Personal Information about you. Specifically, we use cookies  to prevent you from having to reenter your registration data (such as user name and password) at each connection. In addition, we may use information collected by cookies, for other purposes, such as helping us determine how to improve our Websites by seeing which areas and features  are most popular; personalizing the Website and making recommendations based on sections you have linked to in the past; and completing transactions you have requested. Most browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. If you disable this function, some areas of our Websites will not function properly.

Please note that cookies cannot be used to run programs or deliver viruses to your computer.

We maintain log files, which contain Internet Protocol (IP) addresses. An IP address is a numeric address that is assigned to your computer by your Internet Service Provider. We do not link IP addresses to Personal Information, unless we notify you or unless necessary to enforce our Website terms and conditions. In general, we use log files to monitor traffic on our Websites and to troubleshoot technical problems. In the event of abuse, however, we may block certain IP addresses.

NETWORK AND INFORMATION SECURITY

The security and confidentiality of your information is extremely important to us. That’s why we have technical, administrative, and physical security measures in place to protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access and improper use. Personal Information is stored in firewall-protected servers. We will notify users of a data breach involving unencrypted Personal Information by email or by posting a notice on the affected Website. We also strive to limit access to Personal Information to employees performing a legitimate business function. We review our security procedures periodically to consider appropriate new technology and updated methods. Despite our efforts, no security measure is ever perfect or impenetrable. It is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users. If you forget your Momspective password, we will authenticate your identity by sending an email to the address in your account profile.

OPTING OUT

If you do not want us to send you email, regular mail, or other messages, you can opt-out at the time you register for the forum or other information collection. If you have opted-in and, at a later date, wish to have your name removed from our email or regular mail databases, you can log on to the forum and update your preferences in your profile. If you would like to be removed from our mailing lists at any time, please send an email to Jenn. Put the word â€œREMOVEâ€ in the subject line. In the body of the email, please include your name and address and the database(s) from which you would like your information to be removed. Please note that in some instances, despite your opt-out selections, we may send you email communications you have specifically requested or to inform you of important changes to our Website, products or policies.

THIRD PARTY WEB SITES

If you decide to provide Personal Information to any third party website linked from one of our Websites, the sharing of such information will be subject to the privacy policy of that company, not our privacy practices. Be cautious before providing any Personal Information to any third party.

INTERNATIONAL USERS

Visitors to our Websites from outside the United States or Canada are advised that this Privacy Policy is intended to meet the laws and regulations of the United States and Canada, which may not necessarily be the same as the laws and regulations of your home country. By using any of the Websites, you agree that any information that you provide to us will be treated in accordance with the laws and regulations of the United States and Canada.

CONTACT US FOR PRIVACY QUESTIONS, COMMENTS OR CONCERNS

If you have any questions, complaints or comments regarding this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact the Momspective Privacy Policy Administrator via email at Julie@Momspective.com

Click on one of these boxes to share this post!
